Faster. Sharper. Deadlier.
Blade II is a fantasy, horror, action film directed by Guillermo del Toro.
Blade forms an uneasy alliance with the vampire council in order to
combat the Reapers, who are feeding on vampires.
Blade, played by Wesley Snipes.
Whistler, played by Kris Kristofferson.
Reinhardt, played by Ron Perlman.
Nyssa, played by Leonor Varela.
Scud, played by Norman Reedus.
Damaskinos, played by Thomas Kretschmann.
Blade II is a 2002 American superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics character Blade.
It is the second installment in the Blade franchise, following the 1998 film.
It was directed by Guillermo del Toro and written by David S.
The film follows Blade, a human-vampire hybrid, in his
continuing effort to protect humans from vampires.
Blade must join forces with an elite group of vampires to fight against mutant
vampires who plan a global genocide of both vampire and human races.
Blade II was released in the United States on March 22, 2002, and
was a box office success, grossing $155 million.
It received mixed reviews from critics, earning praise for its performances, atmosphere, direction, and
action sequences, although its script and lack of character development have been criticized.
The film was followed by Blade: Trinity in 2004.
The film explores themes of martial arts,
mutation, vampire, lasersight, superhero.
The tone is dark and intense.